（火神(かがみ)）ううっ
（氷室(ひむろ)）ふっ！
（福井(ふくい)）フン！
（木吉(きよし)･火神）くっ うおっ！？
（小金井(こがねい)）うわあ！？ 高い！
So high!
（劉(リュウ)）うっ
He made his shot!
（観客１）決まったー！
（観客２）先取点は陽泉(ようせん)だ
Yosen scores first!
Damn it!
（日向(ひゅうが)）くそっ！
I can't believe Kagami and Kiyoshi gave up that offensive rebound.
（日向）火神と木吉が
オフェンスリバウンドを—
取られるなんて
２メートルは だてじゃねぇ！
They're not just tall for show.
（岡村(おかむら)）うん？ これは！？
This is...
（黒子(くろこ)）くっ…
A Cyclone Pass!
（降旗(ふりはた)）サイクロンパス！
（福田(ふくだ)）カウンターだ！
It's a counterattack!
If we can't score by passing, we'll strike after they score.
（伊月(いづき)）パスワークで
点が取れないなら—
ゴール直後の隙をついてやる！
これなら…
With this strategy...
（伊月）くそ！ 紫原(むらさきばら)！
Damn it, Murasakibara!
What, you're not coming?
（紫原）あれー 来ないの？
Is he going to stay under the net
（火神）こいつ まさか
攻撃には参加せずに—
自陣のゴール下から
動かねえつもりか！？
instead of participating on offense?
だとしたら つけいる隙がねぇ
If that's the case, there's no opportunity for a counterattack.
That's how it is.
（岡村）そういうわけじゃ
ウチにカウンターは効かんぞ
Counterattacks don't work against us.
（劉）
ただ ものぐさってだけアルヨ
He's just lazy though.
I don't like players that won't run, but
（荒木(あらき)）走らない選手など
決して好きではないが—
I make an exception for him and his impregnable defense.
絶対的守備力を持つ
あいつに限っては良しとするさ
（日向）伊月！
（伊月）フン！
Izuki!
（日向）えいっ
（日向）中がダメなら外からだ！
If we can't score from the inside, we'll score from the outside.
（日向）ええいっ
（岡村）ぬぅあ！
（日向）高(たけ)え…
So high!
Damn it!
（火神）くそっ！
タフすぎるぜ このゴール下
It's too hard to score from under the basket!
This isn't good.
（リコ）マズい ディフェンスが
いくら堅いって言っても—
Even though their defense is strong,
it's not as though we can't shoot at all,
シュートが
まったく打てないわけじゃない
but we can't get any rebounds.
けど… リバウンドが取れない
Most players have a shooting percentage around 50 or 60 percent.
（アレックス）フィールドゴールの
確率ってのは—
だいたい５〜６割
In other words, almost half the shots miss.
言いかえれば 半分近いシュートは
外れていることになる
That's why getting rebounds is an important factor as it determines possession, which influences the game.
だからこそ リバウンドの確保は
ボールの支配率に直結し—
勝負を左右する
重要なファクターだ
At this rate, Seirin might really be shut out.
このままじゃマジで—
０点ゲームなんてことも
ありえるぜ 誠凛(せいりん)
shoudou ga atte usoppachi ni idonde
I've got the urge to challenge these bold-faced lies.
boku to kimi to ga shujinkou Love song
You and I are the stars of this love song.
dondon ikimashou
It's time to pick up the pace
Translation Checking: AMS
tsuyoki de semeraretanda
before I lose out to some go-getter,
nakamauchi no warai banashi de wa
and end up like the guys my friends joke about.
Editing: AMS
monmon toshitenda ze
It's starting to drive me crazy...
jibun no heya itsu datte
Always cooped up in my room.
Timing: sangofe
honto wa yowaki na peach mind
The truth is, I've got a timid peach mind
K-Timing: Eternal Blizzard
ki no aru soburi ka
Does she have a thing for me?
Typesetting: AMS, KmE
Karaoke: KmE
tada no omoikomi ka
Or am I reading too much into it?
baretenda ano ko ni wa
Either way, that girl's got us all figured out.
ganbare otoko no ko
Do your best, boys.
Encoding: Your Mom
kono mama ja sanjuugo renpai
If this keeps up, it'll be 35 straight losses.
kimi dake no boku wa Go to guy
But just for you, I'll be your go-to guy.
he
n
ge
ji
za
i
no
ma
ji
ka
ru
su
ta
a
Phantasmagoric magical star
i
da
na
ru
ma
n
ne
ri
da
t
te
i
ja
na
i
What's wrong with a tried-and-true stereotype?
to
me
ro
a
o
sa
wo
Own up to your own inexperience.
ma
da
mi
chi
nu
ko
i
na
ra
ba
If your love has yet to come full circle,
ze
n
bu
a
ge
ru
ze
I'll give you my all.
ki
mi
ni
chi
ka
u
This I swear to you.
saizen-fansubs.com
Seirin
Yosen
Episode
First Basket!!
This isn't good.
（河原(かわはら)）まずいよ まだ１点も…
We haven't scored a single point yet.
There are only 15 seconds left.
（降旗）あと15秒だぞ！？
（黒子）くっ
Their defense is no joke. It's unbelievably strong.
（日向）シャレになんねえ
何つう堅いディフェンスだ
They're not giving an inch.
マジでビクともしねぇ
The level of mental fatigue from a 20-point difference versus an 18-point difference
（リコ）第１クオーターが終わって
20点差と18点差じゃ—
at the end of the first quarter is completely different.
精神的疲労が天と地ほど違う
If we can stop this basket, we can keep fighting.
この一本 止めれば まだ戦える
If we can't though, it'll be fatal.
けど 止められなければ
間違いなく 致命傷になる
（木吉）ええい
（劉）フッ！
（火神）させねえ！ いっ！
No, you don't!
（福井）くっ
（降旗）外れたぁ！
He missed!
But because Kagami jumped for the block,
（日向）けど 火神がブロックに
跳んじまったら—
Kiyoshi and I have to handle these two.
オレと木吉で この２人を！
Wrist curls and hand grips.
（景虎(かげとら)）
リストカールにハンドグリップ
You're strengthening your grip.
なるほど 握力強化か
They're good choices for your big hands.
（景虎）確かに オマエの
でかい手には相性がいい
（木吉）何をすれば
一番チームのためになるか—
It's the conclusion I came to after wondering what I could do to help the team.
考えた結果です
With a passing specialist like Kuroko,
黒子というパスのスペシャリストが
入った今—
what we really need is defensive power.
何より欲しいのは 守る力です
ふーん…
Hm...
In that case, try this.
なら これも やってみろ
Catch it with one hand.
片手で取れ 重いぞ？
It's heavy.
Huh?
A rock?
石？
Catching oddly-shaped heavy objects is the most effective way to strengthen your grip.
握力を鍛えるなら—
実際につかみづらいもんをつかむ
トレーニングが 効果的だ
This certainly seems difficult.
（木吉）これは… キツそうですね
（景虎）何を言ってやがる
What are you talking about?
Didn't you make them a promise?
あいつらと約束したんだろ？
If you want to grab even larger goals, you should be able to grab this easily.
もっと でけえもん
つかみてえんなら—
これぐらいは
余裕でつかんでみせろい
（木吉）負けるか！
I won't lose!
I will defend Seirin's basket!
誠凛のゴール下は オレが守る！
（木吉）ええい
（劉･岡村）うっ
Vice Claw!
（木吉）バイスクロー！
He grabbed an airborne ball with one hand?!
（岡村）空中のボールを
片手でじゃと！？
（木吉）ええい
Kiyoshi!
（伊月）木吉！
He defended the basket!
（降旗）守ったぁぁ！
We can do it!
（小金井）
いけるっ！ まだいけるぞ！！
We're still in this game!
Seirin
Yosen
Eighteen to zero.
（アレックス）18対０か…
Thanks to Kiyoshi's rebound, they're hanging in by a thread,
最後の木吉のリバウンドで
首の皮一枚 つながったが—
依然 ピンチには変わりない
but they're still in trouble.
Let's go over the facts.
（リコ）まず確認よ
They're running a two-three zone.
向こうのフォーメーションは
２(ツー)-３(スリー)ゾーン
Murasakibara's defensive range covers everything inside the three-point line.
紫原君の守備範囲は
３ポイントエリア内すべて—
When you add the other four to that...
そこに 他の４人を加えると…
There's no opening.
（福田）マジで隙ねぇ…
How are we supposed to score like this?
どうやったら
点取れんだよ こんなの
紫原君が真ん中に
陣取ってるおかげで—
With Murasakibara holding his position in the middle,
実際４人は これより
はるかに広く展開して—
the other four are free to move beyond his range and pressure the ball on the outside.
外にもガンガン
プレッシャーをかけてくる
Couldn't we still manage to score a three?
それでも スリーなら
何とか決められるか？
A single shot won't change a thing.
決めたところで
単発じゃ意味がねぇ
In order to win, we have to score inside.
勝つためには—
どうしても
中から取らなきゃダメだ！
Excuse me...
（黒子）あの…
（部員たち）ん？
What?
（さつき）大(だい)ちゃん 早く早く！
Dai, hurry up!
（青峰(あおみね)）あー？ なんでオレまで
来なきゃなんねんだよ！
Why did I have to come too?
You're the one who cancelled our shopping trip at the last second.
（さつき）
買い物 いきなりすっぽかしたの
大ちゃんでしょ！
You can at least make up for it.
埋め合わせぐらいしてよね！
What?!
Seirin
Yosen
E-Eighteen to zero?!
（さつき）じ… 18対０！？
（青峰）おうおう
ギリギリも いいとこじゃねえか
Uh-oh, they're nearly at their limit.
I'm surprised though.
（青峰）とはいえ 驚いたぜ
誠凛の攻撃力は 決してぬるくねぇ
Seirin's offensive power is far from weak.
And that guy managed to shut them out in the first quarter.
それを第１クオーター
０点に抑えたってのか あの野郎
（氷室）うっ
（福井）ええい
（観客１）すっげえ迫力！
（観客２）押し潰されそうだ！
What amazing pressure!
It's like they're being crushed!
Of course it is.
（青峰）そりゃ そうだろう
（さつき）え？
What?
They're trying to finish them off.
とどめ刺しにきてんだ あいつらは
This isn't good.
（アレックス）ヤベェぜ これは
If they don't score now, Seirin's screwed.
開始早々 失点すれば
誠凛のつながった首の皮が切れる
If they don't score on this possession,
この攻めが 無得点で
終わるようなら—
ジ･エンドだ
it'll be the end.
（伊月）ええいっ フンッ！
（福井）あっ…
これは… ７番のポストプレー
This is...
A post play from No. 7!
I won't fail on this play!
（木吉）ここは 絶対に落とさん
What? You think you can get around me like that?
はい？ そんなんで
かわせると思ってんの？
（木吉）ええい
まさか 思ってないよ！
No, of course I don't.
（岡村）本命はこっちか！？
木吉と火神の…
Is this what he was really after?
A combined attack from Kiyoshi and Kagami!
（岡村）
コンビネーションアタック！
（紫原）フンッ
Murasakibara?!
（降旗）紫原！
He's not just big.
（リコ）でかいだけじゃない
なんて反射神経なの！？
What unbelievable reflexes.
It's over.
（荒木）終わりだ
Don't say it's over yet!
勝手に決めんじゃねーよ！
（火神）ええいっ
（黒子）うっ
Let me do it.
（黒子）ボクに やらせてください
（部員たち）ええっ！？
What?
Let you do it? You mean score?
（小金井）やらせてくれって
まさか 点取るってこと
はい
Yes.
I know you practiced shooting,
いくらシュートの
特訓したからって—
but you're up against three two-meter-tall guys.
相手は２メートルが３人だぞ！？
Please.
お願いします
I won't let the game end here.
こんなところで
終わらせません
I will make the shot.
必ず決めます
There's no way Kuro-chin can make a shot.
（紫原）黒(くろ)ちんが
決められるはずがない
But what's this?
なのに… 何だ？
What is that form?
何だ そのフォームは！？
（紫原）ええい！
（火神）な！？
これでも追いつくのか！？
He can still keep up with the ball?
No. Not even you can stop that shot, Murasakibara.
（青峰）いいや そのシュートは
オマエでも止められねーよ 紫原
After all, it's like his drive.
なんせドライブ同様…
消えるぜ それ
It disappears.
All right!
よっしゃー！
Kuroko!
（福田）黒子ー！
（土田(つちだ)）しゃー！
Yeah!
Seirin
Yosen
We finally scored our first points...
（河原）イージスの盾からついに！
（降旗）初得点だ！！
...on the Shield of Aegis!
What?!
No. 11 made a basket?
（岡村）11番が
シュートを決めたじゃと！？
I'd understand if he just made the shot, but...
（福井）決めただけなら
まだ分かる だが…
That mysterious and abnormal form, and...
（劉）謎の変則フォーム そして…
The ball he shot disappeared?
（氷室）打ったボールが…
消えただと！
（紫原）黒ちん！
Kuro-chin!
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
（青峰）10本中６本
こないだより悪くなってねえか？
Six out of ten. Did you actually get worse?
Aomine, how do you shoot?
青峰君は どうやって
シュートしてるんですか？
Like that.
こうだ
I need a more concrete explanation.
（黒子）もう少し具体的に
お願いします
Concrete, huh?
具体的ってもなぁ…
まあ いっそ—
Maybe you'd make more shots if you threw the ball like you're passing to the hoop.
ゴールにパスするつもりで
放ったほうが入んじゃねーの？
Shooting and passing are completely different.
シュートとパスは
全然違います
When I pass, I push the ball with the palm of my hand.
ボクの場合
パスは 手のひらで押す感じで…
Tetsu, shoot it again.
（青峰）テツ もっかい打ってみろ
（黒子）え？
Huh?
（青峰）自分の打ちやすいように
手のひらで 押すように放つんだ
Push the ball with your palm so it's easier for you to shoot.
Seirin
Yosen
（紫原）正直ビックリしたよ
Honestly, I'm surprised.
I didn't think you'd be the first to score against me in this tournament.
まさか 今大会初失点が
黒ちんとはね
Really?
そうですか
In that case, I hope you'll be careful in the future.
じゃあ 以後 気をつけてください
Amazing.
すごい あれが
大ちゃんの特訓の成果！？
Those are the results of training with you?
（青峰）違(ちげ)えよ
（さつき）え？
No.
What?
I just taught him to stop shooting with textbook form.
オレは ただ—
教科書どおりのフォームを
やめさせただけさ
Because Tetsu perfected a unique pass,
テツは 特殊なパスを
極めたゆえに—
he uses his palm when he shoots too.
シュート時にも
手のひらを使っちまう
That's why I made him change his form.
だから フォームのほうを
変えさせたんだ
His form...
（さつき）フォームを…
But the one who turned it into a special technique was Tetsu himself.
（青峰）だが そこから
必殺技にまで 昇華させたのは—
あくまでテツ自身だ
（降旗）来たっ！
（河原）陽泉の攻撃！
They're coming!
Yosen's offense!
（伊月）ええい
Man-to-man defense is their standard.
（福井）基本はマンツー
オレには こいつがついてる
This guy is on me.
No. 7 is on Liu.
劉に７番
Nos. 4 and 11 double team Himuro.
氷室には
４番と11番のダブルチーム
And...
そして…
（岡村）ううっ う…
（火神）ぬおっ
Damn it!
くそっ！
（火神）
こいつ 力ずくでポジションを！
He's securing his position by force.
（岡村）ううっ フン！
（火神）ちっ
（岡村）なんじゃい いたのかぁ？
（火神）あ？
Oh, were you there the whole time?
What?
I forgot. You're just so light.
忘れとったわい 軽すぎて
ううっ… っだとぉーっ！！
What'd you say?
どしたん 水戸部(みとべ)？
What's up, Mitobe?
Coach, Mitobe says it's not working.
（小金井）カントク
水戸部が あれじゃ ダメだって！
（降旗･河原･福田）理解した！？
He understood him?!
I know that.
分かってるわ！
But you and Teppei are the only ones who can face off against Yosen's height.
（リコ）けど 陽泉の高さに
対抗できるのは—
鉄平(てっぺい)と あなただけよ！
Please, Kagami.
お願い 火神君！！
（福井）マジで消えやがる
これが バニシングドライブ！？
He really does disappear!
This is the Vanishing Drive!
It's a disappearing shot!
（劉）消えるシュートか！
Don't be fooled, Liu!
（氷室）つられるな 劉！
（日向）ええい
（劉）あっ
（日向）てやっ
（ホイッスル）
（福田）決まったー！
He made the shot!
Nice shot!
ナイスシュー！
Good. Thanks to Kuroko, we can attack.
（伊月）
いいぞ 黒子のおかげで—
なんとか
攻められる形になってきた
けど 火神は…
But Kagami...
（火神）く… ぐうっ うっ…
（ホイッスル）
（小金井）ダメだ
It's no use. He can't stop him.
やっぱ止められない！
This guy's size and power...
（火神）こいつのサイズとパワー
His movements make it obvious he's a former center too.
しかも
明らかに 元センターの動きだ！
I don't know what to do.
マジでどうすりゃ…
Kagami.
（木吉）火神！
（火神）うっ
Your hips. Drop your hips.
腰だ 腰！ もっと腰を落とせ！
イテーな！ …ですよ
やってるスよ
That hurts!
I'm already doing that!
Don't you have any other advice?
他に何か
アドバイスないんスか！？
他？ ああ…
Other advice?
He's big. You should be careful.
あいつ おっきいから
気をつけろよ
I know that!
（火神）知ってるけど！？
Really? Never mind then.
（木吉）そうか？ ならいいや
（火神）え？
We ran our legs off over the summer to strengthen our hips and legs.
夏に死ぬほど走って
足腰 鍛えただろ？
As long as you remember those two things, you won't lose.
その２つさえ忘れなきゃ
オマエは負けねーよ
（伊月）くっ ていっ
（ホイッスル）
（河原）やった 伊月先輩！
Good job, Izuki!
But...
けど また… 岡村のゴール下！
Okamura's under the net again!
Damn it!
（火神）くっそ とにかく
中に入ってくるのを止めねーと！
In any case, I need to keep him out of the post.
First, I need to lower my hips. Then...
１つは 腰を落として…
もう１つは…
He's big. You should be careful.
あいつ おっきいから
気をつけろよ
There's no second piece of advice!
（火神）つーか ２つ目
あってないようなもんだろが！
はっ 待てよ でかいから
気をつけろってことは…
Hold on.
If I should be careful of his size, that means...
フッ 言ったろ？ 負けねえって
See? I told you you wouldn't lose.
He's not moving!
（岡村）動かん…
You little brat!
小僧！
I figured it out.
分かったぜ
テメエのでかさにつられて—
I subconsciously wasn't lowering my center of gravity enough because of your height.
無意識に重心を
下げきれてなかった
ううっ… ナメるな！ ぐ…
Don't underestimate me!
（岡村）ううっ！
（火神）浅い！
Not deep enough!
I can catch up!
ぐっ そこなら追いつけらあ！！
（火神）おらっ
（岡村）えっ？
What?!
Rebound!
（伊月）リバン
（劉）ふっ もらったぁ！
It's mine!
（木吉）うりゃあ
（福田）バイスクロー！
Vice Claw!
（劉）くっ…
なんてウザい技アル！
What an annoying skill!
Counterattack!
（福田）カウンター！
（紫原）ぬっ！
（日向）ええいっ
（紫原）うっ… 黒ちん！
Kuro-chin!
（部員たち）よっしゃー！
We can do this!
（日向）よし いけるぞ！
（伊月）ほら！
Seirin
Yosen
Wow, we caught up so much in the second quarter!
（降旗）すげえ！
第２クオーターで
ここまで追いついたぁ！
We could take it in the second half!
（河原）いけるぞ 後半！
We will now take a break.
（審判）これより
インターバルに入ります
Kagami.
火神君
あぁ ったく 逆に不気味だぜ
Yeah.
Man, it's eerie.
This isn't all they've got.
あいつらが
こんなもんなはずねえ
The worst is still coming.
おそらく 本当にヤベェのは
これからだ
Yosen still hasn't revealed everything they can do,
（アレックス）
まだまだ 底を見せていない—
陽泉に対して—
誠凛の懸念材料は てんこ盛りだ
and Seirin's got plenty to worry about.
If their offense keeps relying on Kuroko,
黒子に頼りきった
攻めのままでは—
they'll run out of steam in the second half.
後半 必ずツケがくる
What will Seirin do?
どうする 誠凛…？
Seirin should bench No. 11 in the second half.
（荒木）後半 誠凛は
11番 黒子を下げるはずだ
The disappearing shots were a surprise,
消えるシュートには
確かに驚かされたが—
第２クオーター頭まで
出さなかったことから—
but there must be some sort of condition since they didn't put him in until the second quarter.
何らかの条件があることは
間違いない
It's most likely related to his misdirection.
おそらくミスディレクションにも
関係がある
If it is, they'll definitely return him to the bench.
とすれば 必ず一度
ベンチに下げるだろう
This will be accompanied by a change in their formation.
それにともなって—
フォーメーションも
変えてくるはずだ
But they might keep him in like they did against Touou and use his Overflow.
けど 逆に桐皇(とうおう)戦のときのように
出し続けて—
オーバーフローを
使うかもしれませんよ？
No, they won't.
（荒木）いや それはない
（岡村）うん？
なぜなら…
Because...
We can't use Kuroko's Misdirection Overflow against Yosen.
黒子君のミスディレクション･
オーバーフローは—
陽泉相手には使えないわ
えっ なんで！？
What? Why not?
We can't expect the same explosive effect we saw against Touou.
（リコ）桐皇戦のときほど
爆発的な効果が期待できないのよ
Kuroko's Overflow has two effects.
（リコ）黒子君の
オーバーフローの効果は２つ
He increases his team's offensive power by granting them the ability to use the Vanishing Drive.
味方に バニシングドライブの
効果を与える攻撃力アップ
He also increases his team's defensive power by reducing the accuracy of his opponent's shots.
そして相手のシュート精度を下げる
守備力アップよ
The problem lies in the defensive power.
問題なのは守備力のほう
これは
アウトサイドシューターや—
It's highly effective against outside shooters and slashers,
スラッシャーには
効果が高いけど—
but it will hardly have any effect against a team like Yosen that focuses on playing inside.
インサイドプレーを主体とする
陽泉に対しては—
ほとんど効果を発揮できないの
いい？
オフェンスは黒子君抜きで—
We have to score against Murasakibara without Kuroko.
何としても
紫原君から点を取ること
In order to do that, Teppei...
そのためには 鉄平—
Your strength will become important.
あなたの力が重要になる
And defense.
そしてディフェンス
The cornerstone of Yosen's offense will make his move in the second half.
後半 陽泉の攻撃の要である彼が
必ず動くはずよ
No. 12, Himuro.
12番 氷室君
If there's anyone who can stop him, it's Kagami.
彼を止められるとしたら
火神君しかいないわ
In other words, in order for us to win,
つまり ウチが勝つためには—
Kagami needs to beat Himuro,
火神君が 氷室君を—
and Teppei needs to beat Murasakibara.
鉄平が 紫原君を倒すことが
必須条件なのよ
In the second half, Murasakibara's opponent will be Kiyoshi.
よって後半 紫原の相手は木吉
（紫原）ふん…
And you'll handle their ace Kagami, Himuro.
（荒木）そして
エース火神の相手はオマエだ
氷室
Do your best.
しっかりね〜 オレ あいつ嫌い
I hate him. Well, I hate Kiyoshi too.
木吉もだけど 両方 暑苦しい
They're both so intense.
（日向）よっしゃ 行くぞぉ！！
（選手たち）おお！
All right, let's go!
Yeah!
（黒子）木吉先輩 火神君
Kiyoshi, Kagami.
Murasakibara and Himuro are both strong.
紫原君も氷室さんも強いです
But I don't think you'll lose to them.
けど 負けるとは思ってません
Go give it to them.
コテンパンにしてきてください
Of course we will.
ったりめーだろが！
Give it to them, huh? Sounds good.
コテンパンか いいね
Leave it to us!
（火神･木吉）まかせとけ！！
（福井）うっ やはり！
She was right.
They benched Tetsu.
テツを ひっこめてきたか
And this is
しかも これトライアングルツー！
a triangle-and-two defense!
They're completely unaffected by our strategy.
（リコ）こちらの策にも
まったく動揺がないわね
You must've expected this, granny.
ここまでは 読んでたってわけね
オバハン！
Their three-man zone is on Okamura and Liu.
（福井）岡村 劉の
２メートルコンビは—
３人のゾーンで守って
外のオレには こいつ
This guy's on me on the outside.
And then...
Don't get ahead of yourselves.
ったく 急にやる気出しやがって
氷室！
They still had this guy up their sleeve.
（青峰）
まだ こんなヤツがいたかよ
Sorry to keep you waiting.
待たせたな
Don't hold back, Tatsuya!
遠慮なくやろうぜ タツヤ！
I like the look in your eyes. I'm relieved.
いい眼(め)だ 安心したよ
It sounds like what you said before the game was true.
試合前に言っていたことは
本当みたいだね
But I will be the victor, Taiga!
だが勝つのはオレだ タイガ！
kasunda mirai wo kirisaku you ni terasu hikari
Like a shining light that cuts through the hazy future,
musuu no kanousei wo motome
I chase after unlimited possibilities.
Gotta open my eyes
Wake up sabitsuita me ni hi wo tomose
Wake up, light a fire in your tired eyes.
Get up kusubutteru baai ja nainda zettai
Get up! Now's definitely not the time to let it smoulder.
youi sareta risou nante iranai
You don't need to have some big dream.
yuragu koto no nai ishi to
Just an unwavering spirit,
mikansei na chizu de ii kara
and an unfinished map is enough.
asu wo tsukame kono te de
Hold on to tomorrow with these hands!
detarame na rizumu de nurikaete iku kako ni
Regretting a past that's being overwritten by a nonsensical rhythm...
koukai hitotsu arienai daro
That's not possible, right?
ari no mama no biito de kurikaeshite iku genzei wo
I'll rewrite things with the true beat now,
kasaneta mirai kagayaku you ni
and create a sparkling future.
kizami konda sonzai wo kesshou toshite
Your existence is etched as a crystal.
Keep it in my story
Next Episode
It's on, Tatsuya!
（火神）勝負だ タツヤ！
（氷室）本気で来いよ タイガ！
Bring it on, Taiga.
Yeah, we'll settle the score this time!
（火神）ああ 今度こそ
決着をつけてやるぜ！
I like the look in your eyes. I'm relieved.
（氷室）いい眼だ 安心したよ
だがオレのミラージュは破れない！
But you cannot pierce my mirage.
Episode
It's Obvious
Nobody can stop me!
Nobody can stop me！